## Amandip Kaur Sidhu

# Senior Frontend UI Developer

Bathinda, Punjab, India

+917973451552

er.amandip85@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amandipk/

## PROFESSIONAL BACKGROUND

Frontend Developer with 8+ years of experience in Front-end development (converting PSD to XHTML, HTML (5), XHTML, HTML, CSS (3), SASS/SCSS/LESS, UI/UX design, Twitter Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Photoshop, Web Development), and 3.5 years of experience in ReactUS, Figma, NopCommerce, Azure, SEO, HubSpot CMS, and GIT. Hands-on experience in WordPress Astro Build, WooCommerce, ERPNext, Firebase, and DNN.

### **SKILLS**

## **Technical Skills:**

XHTML/HTML5, CSS3/SASS/LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery/JavaScript (Implementations)

Photoshop/XD/Figma (UX: asset extraction and basic editing)

React JS (Theme development, Dynamic UI and API integrations)

NopCommerce (FE-DotNet Framework), HubSpot (Theme Creation & CMS), SEO, ERPNext Custom Theme, Astro Build, WordPress (PHP framework), WooCommerce, DotNetNuke (Dot Net Framework)

## **Industry Skills:**

UX/UI, Web Development, Development Operations, Unit Testing, Debugging, and Usability Research

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Nestorbird Pvt. Ltd.

Mohali, Punjab, India January 2020-PRESENT

#### Senior Frontend Developer (Team Lead)

• Directed and mentored a Ul/front-end team, overseeing code reviews and implementing efficient code deployment strategies; fostered strong cross-functional collaborations with clients, designers, and backend developers, resulting in a 30% reduction in project turnaround time and a 15% increase in client retention rate.

- Successfully created more than five food-based e-commerce websites in NopCommerce—multi-vendor and multi-store.
- Successfully created several websites using **ReactJS**, ensuring high performance and scalability, which led to a 35% increase in overall project efficiency. Developed and implemented a complete theme in ReactJs.
- Converted PSD's, Figma, and XD files into HTML/XHTML using CSS, CSS3, SASS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Less CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, and jQuery to design website templates as per the specifications provided.
- Developed the company's website using Astro Build, which increased the site's performance by 80%.
- Developed and Migrated the website to the HubSpot platform, used HubSpot CMS, and used best practices to improve the SEO performance by 70%.
- Resolved complex **jQuery issues in multiple CMS platforms**, optimized website functionality and reduced page load time by 25%
- Implemented custom-designed **WordPress**, **HubSpot themes**, and other **CMS**, resulting in 40% faster website load times and an improved user experience.

#### CA, United States,

#### Senior Frontend Web Developer, Wordpress CMS

September 2011-October 2016

- Implemented visually stunning designs in WordPress, collaborating with cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration of custom plugins and features; optimized user engagement and conversion rates, leading to a 20% increase in online sales.
- Converted PSDs into XHTML using CSS, CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Resolved UI and jQuery issues to meet client requirements.

#### NZTechnologies Pvt. Ltd./ Dot3 Solutions

Mohali, Punjab, India

January 2009–April 2011

- Senior Frontend Web Developer (Team Lead)
- Led the UI/front-end team and collaborated closely with clients and frontend and backend teams.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to ensure high standards of website design were met.
- Implemented designs in DNN and other CMS, resolving jQuery issues.
- Led the development of new front-end features for the company website, increasing customer engagement and sales by 20% within the first year of implementation.

#### **Zooom IT**

Mohali, Punjab, India

Web Designer

April 2008-December 2008

- Implemented designs in static websites as per the specifications provided.
- Converted PSDs into XHTML using CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery; implemented designs in DNN, Magento, JOJO CMS, WordPress, and other CMS; and resolved jQuery issues.
- Implemented JavaScript as per the requirements, resulting in improved website performance and the creation of desktop, tablet, and mobile-friendly designs, leading to a 97% customer satisfaction rate.

## **EDUCATION**

Symbiosis Centre of Distance Learning / Postgraduate Diploma In Information and Technology

April 2008-March 2010, PUNE, India

Punjab Technical University, Bachelor of Technology

PUNJAB, India

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

CSS Certificate: <u>Hackerrank Certificate</u>

Accessibility for Web Design: LinkedIn Certificate

#### **AWARDS**

Best Mentor Award in Nestorbird Pvt. Ltd.